A Guide to the Records of the Virginia Secretary of Natural Resources, 2002-2014 (bulk 2009-2013)
Library of Virginia
- Series II: Decision Memoranda and Briefs, 2010-2013., Extent: 6 boxes (2.1 cu. ft.). (Box 19-24)
  - Critical Hiring Requests, Dept. of Environmental Quality, 2012 (Box 24, Folder 6)
  - Critical Hiring Requests, Dept. of Game and Inland Fisheries, 2012 (Box 24, Folder 7)
  - Critical Hiring Requests, Dept. of Historic Resources, 2012 (Box 24, Folder 8)
  - Critical Hiring Requests, Marine Resources Commission, 2012 (Box 24, Folder 9)
  - Critical Hiring Requests, Virginia Museum of Natural History, 2012 (Box 24, Folder 10)
  - Critical Hiring Requests, Dept. of Conservation and Recreation, 2013 (Box 24, Folder 11)
  - Critical Hiring Requests, Dept. of Environmental Quality, 2013 (Box 24, Folder 12)
  - Critical Hiring Requests, Dept. of Game and Inland Fisheries, 2013 (Box 24, Folder 13)
  - Critical Hiring Requests, Dept. of Historic Resources, 2013 (Box 24, Folder 14)
  - Critical Hiring Requests, Marine Resources Commission, 2013 (Box 24, Folder 15)
  - Critical Hiring Requests, Virginia Museum of Natural History, 2013 (Box 24, Folder 16)
- Series III: Legislative Files, 2007-2013., Extent: 20 boxes (7 cu. ft.). (Box 25-44)
  Series III: Legislative files, 2007-2013, is housed in twenty boxes and arranged alphabetically by folder title. This series includes agendas, budget materials, conference programs, correspondence, memorandum, newsclippings, presentations, press releases, reports, studies, and other sundry materials. Many of the records in this series contain information on various natural resources-related projects and issues, while other files contain agency-specific administrative information, general correspondence (including a limited amount of constituent correspondence), agency strategic plans, and meeting material, including agendas, print-outs of presentations, and minutes. Topics include energy, offshore wind, uranium mining, water conservation, and others. Of note are several folders relating to Offshore Wind Energy and the Outer Continental Shelf (OCS). There is much overlap between the Offshore Wind and OCS files. The Federal government awarded Virginia with an OCS oil and gas lease sale in March of 2010 but later cancelled the sale.
  Included are legislative action summaries which often contain a summary of the bill; a summary of constituents who would be affected; the recommendation of the agency within the Secretary of Natural Resources as to whether the Governor should sign, veto, or amend the bill; and the recommendation of the Secretary as to whether the Governor should sign, veto, or amend the bill. Legislative action summaries are also included in other series.
  Also included are correspondence and subject files relating to the state agencies that are overseen by the Secretary of Natural Resources: the Department of Conservation and Recreation, Department of Environmental Quality, Department of Game and Inland Fisheries, Marine Resources Commission, and the Virginia Museum of Natural History.
  - American Energy Alliance, 2009-2010 (Box 25, Folder 1)
  - American Petroleum Institute, 2010 (Box 25, Folder 2)
  - Appalachian Power Company, Rate analysis, 2010 (Box 25, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence, General, 2010 (Box 25, Folder 4-5)
  - Dept. of Conservation and Recreation, Management study, 2010-2011 (Box 25, Folder 6)
  - Energy Plan, Environment Virginia Conference, 2010 (Box 25, Folder 7)
  - Energy Plan, Energy Group, 2010 (Box 26, Folder 1)
  - Energy Plan, 2010-2011 (Box 26, Folder 2-3)
  - Enrolled bills, 2011 (Box 26, Folder 4-6)
  - Enrolled bills, 2011 (Box 27, Folder 1)
  - Enrolled bills, 2011-2012 (Box 27, Folder 2)
  - General, 2010 (Box 27, Folder 3)
  - General, 2011 (Box 27, Folder 4-5)
  - Germane EPA Rules, Legislation and Policies, Volume I, 2011 (Box 27, Folder 6)
  - Germane EPA Rules, Legislation and Policies, Volume I, 2011 (Box 28, Folder 1)
  - Germane EPA Rules, Legislation and Policies, Volume II, 2011 (Box 28, Folder 2-3)
  - Governors Energy Summit, Governors Conference on Energy, 2010 October 12-14 (Box 28, Folder 4)
  - Governors Energy Summit, Governors Conference on Energy, Government Reform Commission, 2010 October 12-14 (Box 28, Folder 5)
  - Governors Energy Summit, Governors Conference on Energy, Logo, Marketing, 2010 October 12-14 (Box 28, Folder 6)
  - Governors Energy Summit, Governors Conference on Energy, Miscellaneous, 2010 October 12-14 (Box 28, Folder 7)
  - Governors Energy Summit, Governors Conference on Energy, Planning, 2010 October 12-14 (Box 29, Folder 1)
  - Governors Energy Summit, Governors Conference on Energy, Sponsors, 2010 October 12-14 (Box 29, Folder 2)
  - Governors Energy Summit, Governors Conference on Energy, Timeline, 2010 October 12-14 (Box 29, Folder 3)
  - Governors Energy Summit, Governors Conference on Energy, 2011 October 17-19 (Box 29, Folder 4-5)
  - Governors Energy Summit, Governors Conference on Energy, 2012 October 2-4 (Box 29, Folder 6)
  - Governors Energy Summit, Governors Conference on Energy, 2013 (Box 29, Folder 7)
  - Legislative Action Summary, 2010-2011 (Box 29, Folder 8)
  - Legislative Action Summary, 2011 (Box 29, Folder 9)
  - Legislative Action Summary, House Bills, 2011 (Box 30, Folder 1-2)
  - Legislative Action Summary, Senate Bills, 2011 (Box 30, Folder 3-4)
  - Legislative Action Summary, 2013 (Box 30, Folder 5-7)
  - Legislative Action Summary, 2013 (Box 31, Folder 1-4)
  - Materials regarding MACT (Maximum Achievable Control Technology) Rule, 2010 (Box 31, Folder 5)
  - Materials regarding MACT Rule, 2010 (Box 32, Folder 1-2)
  - Minerals Management Service, 2010 (Box 32, Folder 3)
  - National Coastal and Marine Spatial Planning Workshop, 2011 June 21-23 (Box 32, Folder 4)
  - National Petroleum Council, Advancing Technology for America's Transportation Future, Volume I, 2012 (Box 32, Folder 5-6)
  - National Petroleum Council, Advancing Technology for America's Transportation Future, Volume II, 2012 (Box 33, Folder 1-2)
  - 19th Annual Ethics Program, Litigation Ethics: Part V (Courts), 2010 (Box 33, Folder 3)
  - Offshore Wind, Conference (Virginia Offshore Wind Conference), 2011 June 22 (Box 33, Folder 4)
  - Offshore Wind, Consortium Work (Atlantic Offshore Wind Energy Consortium), 2010 (Box 33, Folder 5)
  - Offshore Wind, Dept. of Defense, 2010-2011 (Box 33, Folder 6)
  - Offshore Wind, Developer's notes, 2010 (Box 33, Folder 7)
  - Offshore Wind, Governor's briefings, 2009-2010 (Box 33, Folder 8)
  - Offshore Wind, Governor's trip, 2010 (Box 34, Folder 1)
  - Offshore Wind, JMU and VT, 2010-2011 (Box 34, Folder 2)
  - Offshore Wind, Lease (Dept. of Mines, Minerals and Energy), 2010-2011 (Box 34, Folder 3)
  - Offshore Wind, Letter, Governor, 2010 (Box 34, Folder 4)
  - Offshore Wind, Letter, President Obama, 2010 (Box 34, Folder 5)
  - Offshore Wind, Letter, U.S. Senate, 2010 (Box 34, Folder 6)
  - Offshore Wind, Maps, ca. 2010 (Box 34, Folder 7)
  - Offshore Wind, Misc. press, 2010-2011 (Box 34, Folder 8)
  - Offshore Wind, Pocantico Offshore Wind Conference, 2011 July (Box 34, Folder 9)
  - Offshore Wind, Poseidon Atlantic LLC, 2011 (Box 34, Folder 10)
  - Offshore Wind, Research and reports, 2010 (Box 34, Folder 11-12)
  - Offshore Wind, Research and reports, 2010 (Box 35, Folder 1)
  - Offshore Wind, Research and reports, 2011 (Box 35, Folder 2)
  - Offshore Wind, Rockefeller Brothers Fund: Accelerating Atlantic Offshore Wind, 2011 (Box 35, Folder 3)
  - Offshore Wind, Status of other states, 2009-2010 (Box 35, Folder 4)
  - Offshore Wind, Task Force meeting (BOEMRE Virginia Task Force), 2010 December (Box 35, Folder 5)
  - Offshore Wind, Virginia Economic Development Partnership, 2010 (Box 35, Folder 6)
  - Offshore Wind, Virginia Offshore Wind Development Authority, 2010-2011 (Box 35, Folder 7)
  - Offshore Wind, Wind RAP (Regulatory Advisory Panel), 2010 (Box 35, Folder 8)
  - Outer Continental Shelf, BOEMRE (Bureau of Ocean Energy Management, Regulation and Enforcement), 2010 (Box 35, Folder 9)
  - Outer Continental Shelf, CZMA (Coastal Zone Management Act), 2010 (Box 35, Folder 10)
  - Outer Continental Shelf, Conference, 2010 May (Box 35, Folder 11)
  - Outer Continental Shelf, Dept. of Defense, 2010 (Box 35, Folder 12)
  - Outer Continental Shelf, Dept. of Interior, 2009-2011 (Box 35, Folder 13)
  - Outer Continental Shelf, Estimates, 2010 (Box 36, Folder 1)
  - Outer Continental Shelf, Governor, 2010 (Box 36, Folder 2)
  - Outer Continental Shelf, Governor's Coalition, 2011 (Box 36, Folder 3)
  - Outer Continental Shelf, Gulf Oil Spill, 2006-2010 (Box 36, Folder 4)
  - Outer Continental Shelf, Thomas Jefferson Institute, 2009 (Box 36, Folder 5)
  - Outer Continental Shelf, Leasing program (Preliminary Revised Program Outer Continental Shelf Oil and Gas Leasing Program 2007-2012), 2010 (Box 36, Folder 6)
  - Outer Continental Shelf, Leasing program (Sale 220), 2010-2011 (Box 36, Folder 7)
  - Outer Continental Shelf, Legislation (H.R. 4942, Virginia Energy Act), 2009-2010 (Box 36, Folder 8)
  - Outer Continental Shelf, Legislation (H.R. 1229, 1230, 1231), 2011-2012 (Box 36, Folder 9)
  - Outer Continental Shelf, Macondo Blowout Conference Call, 2010 May (Box 37, Folder 1)
  - Outer Continental Shelf, Mid-Continent Oil and Gas Association, ca. 2007 (Box 37, Folder 2)
  - Outer Continental Shelf, NASA, 2010 (Box 37, Folder 3)
  - Outer Continental Shelf, NOIA (National Ocean Industries Association), 2008-2010 (Box 37, Folder 4)
  - Outer Continental Shelf, Nature Conservancy, 2008 (Box 37, Folder 5)
  - Outer Continental Shelf, Newsclippings, 2010 (Box 37, Folder 6)
  - Outer Continental Shelf, Offshore Access to Oil and Natural Gas Resources (Report), 2010 (Box 37, Folder 7)
  - Outer Continental Shelf, Offshore Wind (Dominion Offshore Wind), 2010-2011 (Box 37, Folder 8)
  - Outer Continental Shelf, Presentations, 2010 (Box 37, Folder 9)
  - Outer Continental Shelf, Outer Continental Shelf Governor's Coalition, 2013 February (Box 37, Folder 10)
  - Outer Continental Shelf, SEA (Southeast Energy Alliance), 2009-2010 (Box 37, Folder 11)
  - Outer Continental Shelf, U.S. Congress, 2010 (Box 37, Folder 12)
  - Outer Continental Shelf, U.S. Senate, 2010 (Box 37, Folder 13)
  - Outer Continental Shelf, Virginia agencies, 2010 (Box 37, Folder 14)
  - Outer Continental Shelf, Virginia Offshore Wind Development Authority, 2011 (Box 38, Folder 1)
  - Outer Continental Shelf, Wind energy, 2011-2012 (Box 38, Folder 2)
  - Proposed regulations, Dept. of Conservation and Recreation, 2013 (Box 38, Folder 3)
  - Proposed regulations, Dept. of Environmental Quality, 2010-2011 (Box 38, Folder 4)
  - Proposed regulations, Dept. of Environmental Quality, 2011 (Box 38, Folder 5)
  - Proposed regulations, Dept. of Environmental Quality, 2012 (Box 38, Folder 6)
  - Proposed regulations, Dept. of Historic Resources, 2012 (Box 38, Folder 7)
  - Proposed regulations, Natural Resources Advisory Group, 2011 (Box 38, Folder 8-9)
  - Proposed regulations, Offshore energy resources, 2011 (Box 38, Folder 10)
  - Proposed regulations, State Air Pollution Control Board, 2010 (Box 39, Folder 1)
  - Proposed regulations, State Air Pollution Control Board, 2011 (Box 39, Folder 2)
  - Proposed regulations, State Air Pollution Control Board, 2012 (Box 39, Folder 3)
  - Proposed regulations, State Air Pollution Control Board, 2012-2013 (Box 39, Folder 4)
  - Proposed regulations, State Water Control Board, 2010 (Box 39, Folder 5)
  - Proposed regulations, State Water Control Board, 2011 (Box 39, Folder 6)
  - Proposed regulations, State Water Control Board, 2012-2013 (Box 40, Folder 1-2)
  - Proposed regulations, Virginia Soil and Water Conservation Board, 2012 (Box 40, Folder 3)
  - Proposed regulations, Virginia Waste Management Board, 2012-2013 (Box 40, Folder 4)
  - Renewable Energy in America, 2010 (Box 40, Folder 5)
  - State Agencies, Budget, 2010-2011 (Box 40, Folder 6)
  - State Agencies, Chesapeake Bay, 2010 (Box 40, Folder 7)
  - State Agencies, Dept. of Conservation and Recreation, 2011 (Box 41, Folder 1-2)
  - State Agencies, Dept. of Environmental Quality, 2010-2011 (Box 41, Folder 3-4)
  - State Agencies, Dept. of Game and Inland Fisheries, 2011 (Box 41, Folder 5-6)
  - State Agencies, Dept. of Historic Resources, 2011 (Box 41, Folder 7)
  - State Agencies, Earth Week, 2010 (Box 42, Folder 1)
  - State Agencies, Fort Monroe, 2010 (Box 42, Folder 2)
  - State Agencies, Dept. of the Interior, 2010 (Box 42, Folder 3)
  - State Agencies, Invasive species, 2005-2010 (Box 42, Folder 4)
  - State Agencies, Legislative proposals, 2011-2012 (Box 42, Folder 5)
  - State Agencies, Marine Resources Commission, 2011 (Box 42, Folder 6)
  - State Agencies, Shelburne Glebe, 2011 (Box 42, Folder 7)
  - State Agencies, Virginia Museum of Natural History, 2011 (Box 42, Folder 8)
  - Uranium, Presentation: No Uranium in Virginia, 2012 (Box 42, Folder 9)
  - Uranium, Presentation: Virginia Uranium, Inc., 2012 (Box 42, Folder 10)
  - Uranium, Report of the National Research Council Committee, 2011 (Box 42, Folder 11)
  - Uranium, Uranium Study: Final Report, 2012 (Box 43, Folder 1-4)
  - Uranium, Misc., 2012-2013 (Box 43, Folder 5)
  - Uranium, Working group, 2011-2012 (Box 44, Folder 1-2)
  - Uranium, Working group, Report, 2012 (Box 44, Folder 3-4)
  - Wind consortium, 2010 (Box 44, Folder 5)
- Series IV: Public Relations, Activities, and Visits, 2010-2013., Extent: 3 1/2 boxes (1.2 cu. ft.). (Box 44-47)
  Series IV: Public Relations, Activities, and Visits, 2010-2013, is housed in three and a half boxes and with general materials arranged to the front. This series includes agendas, directions, event schedules, invitations, newsclippings, and other sundry materials. The bulk of the series include invitations to Douglas W. Domenech and Maureen Matsen.
  - AWEA Offshore Windpower, 2013 October 22-23 (Box 44, Folder 6)
  - CBF Brock Environmental Center, nd (Box 44, Folder 7)
  - Germanna Foundation, 2013 October 3 (Box 44, Folder 8)
  - Southern States Energy Board, 2013 October 13-15 (Box 44, Folder 9)
  - Virginia Preservation Conference, 2013 October 20-22 (Box 44, Folder 10)
  - Visits to State Parks, nd (Box 44, Folder 11)
  - Douglas W. Domenech, Yes, 2010-2013 (Box 44, Folder 12)
  - Douglas W. Domenech, Yes (Box 45, Folder 1-3)
  - Douglas W. Domenech, Pending, 2010-2013 (Box 45, Folder 4)
  - Douglas W. Domenech, No (Box 45, Folder 5)
  - Douglas W. Domenech, No, 2010-2013 (Box 46, Folder 1-3)
  - Maureen Matsen, Pending, 2010-2012 (Box 46, Folder 4)
  - Maureen Matsen, No, 2010-2012 (Box 46, Folder 5)
  - Maureen Matsen, No, 2010-2012 (Box 47, Folder 1)
  - Anthony Moore, 2011-2012 (Box 47, Folder 2)